Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1859-1947. Series I of the Mary Earhart Dillon Collection, 1904-1946: A Finding Aid
Papers, 1904-1946, n.d.
M-133, reel E11; A-68
Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute
Carrie (Lane) Chapman Catt, 1859-1947
#1-12
Series I of the Mary Earhart Dillon Collection.
Accession number: 56-121
Access Restrictions:
Access. ORIGINALS CLOSED. USE MICROFILM. REQUEST AS: M-133, REEL E-11.
BIOGRAPHY
Carrie Chapman Catt, leader in the woman suffrage and international peace movements, succeeded Susan B. Anthony as president of the National American Woman Suffrage Association (1900-1904) and was again president when the 19th Amendment to the Constitution was adopted. She was also president of the International Woman Suffrage Alliance, helped found the League of Women Voters of the U.S., and helped organize and chaired the National Committee on the Cause and Cure of War.
For additional biographical information, see Notable American Women (Cambridge, Mass., 1971), which includes a list of additional sources.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
Collection includes biographical information, and articles and speeches by Catt.
There is related material at the Schlesinger Library; see Carrie Chapman Catt papers in the Woman's Rights Collection, 1904-1947 (M-133, reel A1; WRC 37-43).
INVENTORY
- Biographical, 1-5:
  - Autobiographical: fragment of speech and interview, n.d., 1.
  - Correspondence, mostly with biographer (Constance Burnett), 1944-1946, 2.
  - Articles by others, 3-5:
    - 1924-1930; includes complete issue of The Woman Citizen, Sept. 6, 1924., 3.
    - [1909], 1931, 4f.
    - 1935-1945; includes complete issue of The American Girl, April 1945., 5.
- Articles and speeches by CCC, 6-12:
  - Re: suffrage and woman's rights, 6-9:
    - 1904-1919, 6.
    - 1923-1939, 7.
    - "Inheritance of the Woman's Movement," 1938, 8.
    - Award acceptance speech, 1941, 9.
  - Published in The Woman Citizen, 1921-1927; includes editorials., 10.
  - Re: peace, 1921-1931, n.d., 11.
  - Re: prohibition, anti-feminism in South America, money, etc., ms. and printed, 1921-1930, n.d., 12.
Additional catalog entries
The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this series. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases.
Burnett, Constance (Buel); Anti-communist movements-United States; Civics; Conference on the Cause and Cure of War; International Council of Women; League of Women Voters (U.S.); Peace; Permanent Court of International Justice; Prohibition-United States; Women-Suffrage